Mr. Grey will see you now.
Fifty Shades of Grey is a drama, romance, thriller
film directed by Sam Taylor-Johnson.
When college senior Anastasia Steele steps in for her sick roommate to interview prominent businessman
Christian Grey for their campus paper, little does she realize the path her life will take.
Christian, as enigmatic as he is rich and powerful, finds
himself strangely drawn to Ana, and she to him.
Though sexually inexperienced, Ana plunges headlong into an affair -- and learns that
Christian's true sexual proclivities push the boundaries of pain and pleasure.
Anastasia Steele, played by Dakota Johnson.
Christian Grey, played by Jamie Dornan.
Carla, played by Jennifer Ehle.
Kate, played by Eloise Mumford.
José, played by Victor Rasuk.
Elliot Grey, played by Luke Grimes.
Fifty Shades of Grey is a 2015 erotic romantic drama film directed by
Sam Taylor-Johnson from a screenplay by Kelly Marcel.
Produced by Focus Features, Michael De Luca Productions, and
Trigger Street Productions, it is based on E.
James' 2011 novel of the same name, and serves as the first
installment in the Fifty Shades film series.
Starring Dakota Johnson, Jamie Dornan,  Jennifer Ehle and Marcia Gay Harden, the film's story follows Anastasia "Ana"
Steele, a college graduate, who begins a sadomasochistic relationship with young business magnate Christian Grey.
Development of the film commenced in March 2012, when Universal and Focus
Features secured the rights to the trilogy following a bidding war.
After Marcel was hired to write the film's screenplay, multiple directors, including Joe Wright, Patty
Jenkins, Bill Condon, Bennett Miller, and Steven Soderbergh, were attached to the film.
Taylor-Johnson was confirmed as the director in June 2013.
She cited 9½ Weeks (1986), Last Tango in Paris (1972), and Blue Is the
Warmest Colour (2013) as her inspirations for the film.
The main cast joined the project between October and December 2013.
Principal photography commenced in December 2013 and concluded in February 2014.
Reshoots involving scenes between Dornan and Johnson took place
in Vancouver during the week of October 2014.
Danny Elfman was hired to compose the film's score.
Fifty Shades of Grey premiered at the 65th Berlin International Film Festival on February 11,
2015, and was released in IMAX formats on February 13, by Universal Pictures.
Despite receiving generally unfavorable reviews from critics, it was an immediate box office success, breaking
numerous box office records and earning $569.7 million worldwide against a budget of $40 million.
The soundtrack album was also successful; "Love Me like You Do", by English singer Ellie Goulding, was nominated for the Golden Globe Award for Best Original
Song, while "Earned It", by Canadian singer the Weeknd, was nominated for the Academy Award for Best Original Song at the 88th Academy Awards.
The film was the most awarded at the 36th Golden Raspberry Awards, winning five of six
nominations, including Worst Picture (tied with Fantastic Four) and both leading roles.
Fifty Shades of Grey was succeeded by two sequels: Fifty Shades Darker, and Fifty Shades Freed, released in 2017 and
2018, respectively, both of which received similar negative critical reception but commercial success.
The film explores themes of bad smell, based on novel or
book, eroticism, perversion, spanking.
The tone is emotional and intense.